Guide to the Robert Moody papers, 1842-1978.
Moody, Robert papers, 1842-1978.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert Moody papers, 1842-1978.
2473
Robert Moody.
20.6 cubic ft.,
Letters, programs, deeds, newspaper clippings, notes, cemetery records, diaries, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Letters, programs, deeds, newspaper clippings, notes, cemetery records, a diary (1881), a history of Rushville (1788-1934), and other records pertaining to early settlers, local families, and events in Rushville. Also, "Centennial Celebration of the Congregational Church of Rushville, N.Y." (1902) and "The Pioneer Church, 1802-1952," a sesquicentennial history of the Rushville Church by Robert Moody. Also, farm records, diaries, local government records, Mapes estate papers, and Ringer estate papers. Also positive microfilm copy of "Centennial Celebration of the Congregational Church of Rushville, N.Y."
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert Moody graduated from Cornell University in 1918, became a teacher, and served as the Gorham, New York, town historian after his retirement.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters, programs, deeds, newspaper clippings, notes, cemetery records, a diary (1881), a history of Rushville (1788-1934), and other records pertaining to early settlers, local families, and events in Rushville. Also, "Centennial Celebration of the Congregational Church of Rushville, N.Y." (1902) and "The Pioneer Church, 1802-1952," a sesquicentennial history of the Rushville Church by Robert Moody. Also, farm records, diaries, local government records, Mapes estate papers, and Ringer estate papers. Also positive microfilm copy of "Centennial Celebration of the Congregational Church of Rushville, N.Y."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Moody, Robert,; Mapes family.; Moody family.; Ringer family.; First Congregational Church (Rushville, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Religious institutions--New York (State)--Rushville.
Places:
Rushville (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Rushville (N.Y.)--History.; Rushville (N.Y.)--Genealogy.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Related collection: General Store Accounts, #2494.
Related collection: Gorham (N.Y.). Miscellany, #3669.
Related collection: Middlesex Valley Central School. Records, #2237.
CONTAINER LIST
- "Pages from our Local History," Marcus Whitman Historical Society Newsletter, 1973-1985. (Box 1)
- Surrogates Court records on Maude Moody, 1899-1907. (Box 1)
- Town of Gorham records (Box 1)
- Farm and personal records (Box 1)
- NYS Wool Growers Asso. records, 1919-1928 (Box 1)
- Geneva Material from George Waldo. (Box 1)
- Assemblyman Vernon Blodgett Papers, 1950s. (Box 1)
- Rushville historical items. (Box 1)
- Judge Ed Murphy, Texas, 1940. (Box 1)
- Militia of Rushville, 1826. (Box 1)
- Ontario County Board of Supervisors records. (Box 1)
- Account books, 10 vols. (Box 2)
- Assemblyman Vernon Blodgett Papers, Mrs. Blodgett's Albany scrapbook. (Box 3)
- Mina Dewey papers. (Box 3)
- Notes on the history of Rushville for REM's book. (Box 3)
- Farm and personal records. (Box 3)
- Account books for Allen's Ford Garage, Rushville Evaporating and Packing Company records [operated by REM's father?]. (Box 3)
- Blodgett's scrapbook. (Box 4)
- Moody farm account, 1919. (Box 4)
- Allen's Garage account. (Box 4)
- Rushville Evaporating and Packing books. (Box 4)
- Wm. Ledgerwood, Gorham, May 16, 1843. (Box 4)
- Ontario County Justice of the Peace books, 1983, 1870s. (Box 4)
- Moody family papers, correspondence, 1920s-1930s, some with CU. (Box 5)
- Arlington Mapes, CU Class of 1883, papers, correspondence, trade cards, account, ca. 1880-ca. 1915; also Ringer family papers [Mapes' sister, Ella, married Richard Ringer]. (Box 6)
- Diaries, trade cards, guide books, maps and souvenirs of the World's Colombian Exposition. (Box 7)
- Mapes family letters and business correspondence, 1880s-1930s; Richard and Ella Ringer papers. (Box 8-10)
- Mapes Estate [earliest material a letter addressed to Minerva Barden, Michigan, from Geneva, NY], 1840-1890s; A. Mapes' CU papers and notebooks. (Box 11)
- Arlington Mapes papers, some CU items, general farm business regarding sprayers, fertilizers and equipment, valentines, 1870-1930; Richard Ringer. (Box 12-14)
- [No Box 15.] (Box 15)
- Same, including class notes and expenses for four years at CU, 1883-1931; Moody material including the founding of the NYS Sheep Growers Asso. (Box 16)
- Diaries, George Walther, 1871-1930 [1873 not found]. (Box 17)
- Diaries, Robert E. Moody, 1930-1965, 1969, 1972-1973, 1976, 1980-1985; trip to Paris. [Other recent REM diaries are still in Mrs. Moody's possession.] (Box 18)
- Diaries
  - Robert E. Moody, 1904-1929. (Box 19)
  - Emma H. Sterns, 1892-1915. (Box 19)
  - Edward L. Moody, misc. numbers. (Box 19)
  - Edith J. [wife of Ed. L.?], misc. numbers. (Box 19)
  - Mary Ann Moody, 1867, 1870-1872, 1874, 1876. (Box 19)
  - Alice Moody, misc. 6 vols. between 1912 and 1936. (Box 19)
  - Hiram Harkness, 1863-1885 with a few missing. (Box 19)
  - Sarah Harkness, 1917-1918, 1920. (Box 19)
  - 15 vols. of misc. diaries and accounts. (Box 19)
- Ethel Moody school work including a Ph.D. at CU in 1927 (?) in Math. (Box 20)
- REM speeches, 1937-1948. (Box 20)
- Ontario County Civil Service Commission minutes. (Box 20)
- Use of POWs on farm in 1944. (Box 20)
- Arlington Mapes papers. (Box 20)
- Seven vols. of farm accounts. (Box 21-22)
- Diaries, Robert E. Moody, 1966-1981, 1983 (1982 missing). (Box 23)
- Class notebooks of Arlington Mapes, 1880-1883. Science of Finance, Modern History 1881, German, Botany, Romance Literature and Latin Notes, Rhetoric, Moral Philosophy, Comparative Philosophy, American Law and Jurisprudence, Chemical Practice, French. (Box 23)